Arti Pandey

Educator (Science)

Address: Agra, Uttar Pradesh, 282005

Contact No. +91-9760651993 E-mail: <u>arti.dei25@gmail.com</u>



Professional Summary

Compassionate, student-minded Science educator, with almost 4 years of experience in teaching. Passionate to provide an inspiring learning experience to students.

Skills

Good verbal and written communication skills
Time Management
Student records management
SMART Boards
Curriculum Development
Group and individual instruction
Classroom management
Student engagement

Work Experience

2022-03 - Present

TGT Science

Shri Ram Centennial School, Agra

- Using multidisciplinary approach in teaching
- Planning and implementing lab-based science lessons based on school standards.
- Used Activity based leaning.
- > Students were taken to practical labs, science-park for the development of their affective and psychomotor domain.
- > Frequently conducted Parent-teacher meetings for clearly monitoring students.

➤ Participated in school activities including staff development, departmental meetings, and grade team meetings to discuss ways in which to improve teaching strategies.

2019-05 to 2020-03

TGT Chemistry

Army Public School, Agra Cantt

- From APS I have experience class 6th, 7th, 9th, and 10th.
- ➤ Get all the children to participate in the teaching-learning process so that the classroom environment becomes interactive.
- Planned innovative lesson plans.
- Emphasized on learning by doing method.
- Used Activity based leaning.
- > Students were taken to practical labs, science-park for the development of their affective and psychomotor domain.
- ➤ Topic related activities were demonstrated so that students are more connected to that topic.
- Indirect feedback was taken so that individual needs can be better understand.
- For the active participation of students quizzes and seminar were taken.
- ➤ Projects, models made by students were shown at the Parent-teacher meeting.

2015-10 to 2017-04

PGT Chemistry

ESS ESS Convent Sr. Sec. School, Agra

- From ESS ESS I have experience class 9th, 10th, 11th, and 12th
- ➤ Gave practical knowledge along with theoretical knowledge, for which they got, introduced to the chemistry lab, told safety rules, and got practical's done.
- ➤ Students were taken to Inter School Science competition.
- > Frequently conducted Parent-teacher meetings for clearly monitoring students.
- ➢ Based on student needs extra classes were provided to class 10th & 12th students.

Education

- B.Ed. (Biology, science) 2015
 Dayalbagh Educational Institute
 7.29(CGPA)
- M.Sc. Chemistry 2014
 Dayalbagh Educational Institute
 7.47(CGPA)
- B.Sc. (Botany, Chemistry)- 2012

 Dayalbagh Educational Institute
 7.65(CGPA)
- Intermediate- 2009
 P.V. Girls Intermediate College, Agra
 68.9(Percentage)
- High School- 2007
 P.V. Girls Intermediate College, Agra
 72.8(Percentage)

Project

M.Sc. Dissertation (Jul'13 -Dec'13): Sonolytic Sorption of Disperse Red 167:1 in the presence of TiO2 & Gadolinium.

- The *objective* of this work was to examined the removal of Disperse Red 167:1 dye either through degradation or adsorption in the presence of ultrasound (US), Titanium Dioxide (TiO2), used as adsorbent and, Rare earth ion (Gd), promoter for absorption
- *Instruments* used during the conduction of experiment were UV Spectrophotometer and Ultrasonic Cleaning Bath.
- *Results* showed that US when combined with Rare Earth ions (Gd) enhanced the degradation percentage.

Accomplishments

- 2023- Attended 5 hours offline in-house training workshop on CBSE backed Engage Model Lesson Plan conducted by Voice of Choice.
- 2021- Passed CCC (Course on Computer concepts) exam conducted by NIELIT.
- 2021- CSB qualified
- 2019- CTET qualified(both Paper I & Paper II)
- 2017- Participated in charity event: "RUN FOR HER."
- 2015- Won First prize in Hindi skit at University level.
- 2014- Scouting/ Guiding Certificate.
- 2011- Served in NSS (National Service Scheme) camp for 7 days.
- 2009- Completed course on Computer.
- 2009- NCC Certificate (A, B & C)
- 2007- 2 Years Russian Language Course.

Computer Skills

Proficient with MS Office Programs-

MS Word, Excel & PowerPoint.

Completed Course on Elementary Infotech.

Passed CCC exam conducted by NIELIT

Language

- Hindi
- English
- Russian (Basic)